Guide to the Otto Kinkeldey papers, 1902-1966.
Kinkeldey, Otto papers, 1902-1966.
- Series V. Notes and printed materials, 1901-1953
  - from Dr. Ercdmann, description and criticism of "Der Pierrot," Monodrama von Otto Suchland, mit Musik von Hans Erdmann, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - from Dr. Ercdmann, memoirs of WWI, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Bibliographic Notes, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Lecture Notes from Opera first term, 1925-1926 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Invoices, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Notes, The Harmonic Series (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Biographic and Bibliographic Notes (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Biographic Notes (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Notes (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Bibliographic Notes (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Notes (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - "Musik in Schlesien," mss. notes (copies) (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - "Musik in Schlesien," mss. notes (copies) (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Programs and newsclippings re Kinkeldey, 1924-1953 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Notes (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Notes (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Beethoven Bibliographic Notes (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Bibliography with Notes from Pepys' Diary (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Notes on William Henry Fry (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Notes on Graduals (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Beethoven Notes (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Classification system of books on music at Staatsbibiothek, Berlin (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Misc. Notes (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Misc., certificates, lists, etc. (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Bibliographic Notes (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Pamphlet: Rules of Etiquette and Dress, 1681 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Two mss. music scores, 1733 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Music Scores, 1759 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Concert Program, Feb. 12, 1764; Pamphlet, Guide to Mohra, 1871; Bibliographic Notes (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Mss. Music Score, 1788 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Mss. Exercise Book for Bass Voice, c. 18th Century (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Mss. Copy of 1591 Music Score (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Music Score (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous materials and material from a file; pamphlets, music scores (ms., engraved and printed), programs, correspondence, patent, lecture notes
  - Cataloging: Germany, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Cataloging: Germany, 1911-1913 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Programs, includes Dedication of Organ at St. Patrick's Cathedral, N.Y.; 1902, 1911, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - A, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - B, 1910-1913 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Breslau Lecture Notes (5 Sets) 1909 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Breslau (includes patent for Elecktrische, direkt wirkende Orgeltraktur) 1911-1913 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - D, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - E, 1913-1914 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - F; 1912, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - G; 1911, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Guttmann includes draft of "Zur Physiologie und Psychologie des Singens und Sprechens" (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Guhrau, Gerbruder Walter, pamphlet, "Uber Pflege und Erhaltung der Orgel," 1905 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - H; 1912, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - I, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - J, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - K; 1910, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - L, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - M, 1911-1912 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - O; 1910, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Princeton, 1950-1951 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - R, 1912-1913 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Siebs, 1910-1913 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - S, 1910-1912 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Strauss, Richard Notes (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - V, 1910-1914 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Unidentified and misc. (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - "American Musicians and Composers," and other mss. and drafts for Dictonary of Modern Music, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Music Examinations 1927 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Production of "Orfeo," 1913 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - "Breslau - Organ Revision Papers - Palestrina and Bach Newspaper Note," 1909-1911 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - "Cock Crow" (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Music Composition, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Harmony Book I, 1900-1901 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Harmony Book II, 1900-1901 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Harvard Summer Scool, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Music Problems, Music 100b, May 1947 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Music Problems, Music 100b, Grace E. Lawless, May 1947 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Opera Announcements, K.K. Hof-Operntheatre; 1898, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Printed Matter (Box 12, Folder 48)
    1. The Ballad Burlesques and Extravaganzas; II Current Chronicle; Walter H. Rubsamen, reprint from The Musical Quarterly, 1950
    2. Robert Schumannund die Romantik in der Musik, von Wilibald Gurlitt, 1950
    3. Music Research in Italian Libraries, Walter Rubsamen, reprint from the quarterly journal of the Music Library Association, NOTES, Vol. VI, nos. 2 and 4, and Vol. VIII, no. 1, Mar. 1949-Sept. 1949 and Dec. 1950
    4. La Cliquette, un Instrumrnt d'Oercussion Egyptien de l'Epoque Copte par Dr. H. Hickmann. Le Caire Imprimerie de l'Institut Francais d'Archeologie Orientale, 1950
    5. A Selection of Rare Music and Music Literature catalogue, Otto Haas, London
    6. The Commonwealth of Art, a lecture delievred by Curt Sachs, Apr. 25, 1949, Washington, 1950
    7. Catalogue of Rare and Interesting Books. Myers and Co. Ltd., London
- Series VII. Photographs, artifacts, memorabilia
  - Includes Harris Townsend Medal for Notable Achievement, CCNY, 1940; autographed picture (copy) of Lane Cooper; framed portrait (unidenified); snapshots (unidenified); photos of Kinkeldey; photo album; ceremonial ribbon; guest book to the Kinkeldeys, from their friends in Ithaca, NY, 1946-1953; banquet program/menus (Box 13)
- Series VIII. Diplomas and certificates
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, May 13, 1942 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, 1934 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Princeton, L.H.D., Apr. 3, 1947 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - NYU, A.M., June 7, 1900 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Berlin, P.h. D., June 26, 1909 (Mapcase-folder 1)